

Thamizharasu M

AWS DevOps Engineer

IT Professional and Technology enthusiast with a total of 4+ years of work experience including 2 years of experience as an ERP consultant and 2+ years of experience as an AWS DevOps Engineer for a University Press Project. Experience with DevOps essential tools like Ansible, Docker, GIT, Jenkins, Maven, Tomcat, and Managed Services like EC2. Having knowledge of Container Management and Orchestration Software like Kubernetes. Recognized by the project team for Guidance & Mentoring excellence.

thamizharasu007@gmail.com



7904283330



Chennai, India



in linkedin.com/in/devopstam

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate- Projects Cognizant Technology Solutions

01/2022 - Present

India

Roles & Responsibility

- Worked as AWS DevOps Engineer on Oxford University Press Project.
- Setting up EC2 instances and prerequisites on the instances for deploying the applications
- Worked on Jenkins by installing, configuring, and maintaining Jenkins for automated builds and deployments
- Managing the working environments through the configuration management tool Ansible
- Worked on Ansible Playbooks to bring the required infrastructure changes
- Experience in Docker like creating Docker images, containers, Docker files, tagging and pushing to Docker Hub
- Created and managed multiple containers using Kubernetes, & creating deployments using Yaml code

Associate Software Engineer Accenture Solutions Pvt. Ltd

11/2018 - 12/2021

India

7.35

93%

Prometheus

Achievements/Tasks

- Analyzed and resolved the L2 incidents related to Direct procurement, Logistics, Inventory Management within the given SLA time
- Handled issues related to Sales order processing, Pricing conditions, Schedule Line Agreements in SAP
- Configuration of Enterprise Structure and Assignment of organizational elements like Sales Organization, Distribution Channel, Division, Sales Office, Sales group & Shipping point
- Deployed the Front End Web-page for a Pharmaceutical project using Tomcat web-server
- · Conducted trainings on each tools for the colleagues regarding the tool functionalities

EDUCATION

B.Tech(Information technology) Easwari Engineering College

HSC(Computer Science with Mathematics) Prince Matriculation Higher Secondary School

2013 - 2014

CERTIFICATIONS

DevOps Project- CI/CD with Jenkins, Ansible & Kubernetes from Udemy (2022)

AWS DevOps certification from Cognizant (2022)

SKILLS

ERP Implementation and Support

AWS DevOps

Continuous Integration

Continuous Deployment

Continuous Delivery

Continuous Monitoring

Continuous Testing

Cloud Deployment

AWS Services

ACHIEVEMENTS

Awarded 'Best Performer' by the Project Client in the year 2022-23

Recognized as 'Client Comforter' by the Project Client consecutively twice in the year 2020-21

APPLICATION TOOLS

Linux	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet
AWS	• • • • •
Git	• • • • •
Maven	• • • • •
Jenkins	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
Tomcat	• • • • •
Ansible	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
Docker	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet
Kubernetes	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet